So I'm not really thinking here, I am just saying. 3.14159265358.
I can recite the first thousand digits or so in six minutes-ish, and then the next thousand digits, I was able to recite that in about 20 minutes.
Hi, my name is Annika and I'm a junior in bioengineering here at UMD.
I've really liked challenging myself to memorize things.
I remember my mother once spoke about someone who was able to memorize all the world capitals, and I was like, oh, that's cool, why don't I try that?
When I think about pi, you first have to structure it so that your brain can understand it.
These blocks are thousands. You split it into ten fractions, and these are the hundreds.
As opposed to trying to memorize things in one big sequence, I create a little matrix that I can individually put information in each one of those cells in my mind so I can recall it as I need to.
Then this hundred is split into tens, and then this ten is your digits.
When you're studying for a spelling test, for example, would it be easier to remember the spelling of a hundred letter word, or ten letter words, and the order of ten of those in a sentence?
I don't just rote-memorize anything, because I feel like that is not quite as fun as finding patterns within the things you memorize.
So all I have to do to memorize this one is remember, oh, seven and two is nine, I skip the next one, four and five is nine.
This is almost like a sandwich. You just have to remember three, eight, four between the two ones.
From one to one thousand, I can pinpoint any digit. So if you gave me like six hundred and eighty-seven, I'd be able to give you the six hundred and eighty-seven digit.
Being able to keep practicing that recall, I think, there are benefits of that, like, outside of just pi.
And so it helps me in class, because then I can just recall information.
My favorite number, over here, I don't think I have a supersonic brain.
I think I have a pretty normal brain, but I've been able to kind of optimize these things.
I taught my friend how to memorize pi with the same explanation.
He was able to get to 200 digits in four days as a beginner. It works.